All right guys so we're gonna get started here and I basically just have an edge ledger underscore Web
site folder that's completely empty and I open that within V.S. code so you're going to want to do the
same.
And then in this lecture you'll find an image resources zip file.
So you want to unzip that and we just want to grab all the images that are here and we'll copy these
into our edu ledger Web site folder.
We want to create a folder called EMG and we want to paste those images in there.
OK.
And then if we go back into v s code you can see we have our images to work with.
So let's create our structure here.
Obviously going to need an index study each time l and this is the only aged female page we need because
this is a single page Web site.
Everything is on one page.
We just have different areas that the menus go to.
And this is common.
I'm sure you guys have seen this before and it's actually easier because you don't need as much copy
as much markup our content I should say you know if you just want one section to have a paragraph and
some list items that's fine and you don't have to think of all this this content and people don't want
a ton of content to have to read through they want everything just very simple and easy to read and
understand.
And I think having single page Web sites like this really really helps with that rather than than them
having to search through all these pages.
So let's put in our boilerplate here actually let's create the rest of the file structure.
We need to see assess folder and in CSX we're gonna have a style dot CSX file.
We're also going to have a mobile dot CSX file and we're gonna have a wide screen DOD CSX because I
want to style the icons differently depending on on if it's on a wide screen.
And then we're also gonna have a J S folder so javascript and we're gonna have a file inside there called
Main dot J S which is gonna have the javascript for the Google map as well as the smooth scrolling because
we can't do that when we actually need a little bit of JavaScript for that for the smooth scrolling
we're gonna use something called J query which is a javascript library to do all sorts of things.
Animation is is pretty much the only thing that I would use J query for these days.
So something like this smooth scrolling is much much easier with J.
Query.
But we'll get to that later.
So let's close all these up except for index and then we're going to continue on here.
So for the title I'm just going to say edge ledger financial and let's put a pipe character and then
we'll see accounting and investment.
OK.
Let's put all all of our CSX files so we'll say link tab or link enter and I'm going to say CSX slash
style CSX and I'm going to copy this so can shift option or shift Ault on windows down twice this first
one I'm going to change to mobile the second one I'm going to change to widescreen and we need to add
media queries or media attributes for mobile and widescreen so let's say screen and we want a max width
of seven sixty 68 pixels OK and then for widescreen let's do media equals screen.
And this time we want to do men with and we want eleven hundred pixels so this will only kick in when
the screen is bigger than eleven hundred pixels.
OK.
And we're also going to be using font awesome so let's head over to font awesome dot com and click this
button here and grab the link so that we can incorporate icons will pace set in there and our head should
be all set.
So let's go ahead and open this up and we're going to going to have a blank page we have an ad in anything
yet so going to start with the nav bar obviously we're going to go top to bottom and I put the nav bar
outside of the showcase outside of this header with the idea of showcase and the reason for that is
we're using a sticky nav bar and if we put it inside of the showcase or in the header here what's going
to happen is once we reached the bottom it's going to disappear because it's basically stuck inside
of its parent.
So we don't want this to have a parent.
So we want to put the nav bar above the showcase.
OK.
So let's go into body and let's do nav tag and we want to put an I.D. nav bar and we want inside here
in H1 we'll give it a class of logo.
And inside this H1 as you can see we have an icon.
And then these are both going to be green.
So we need a special class for that.
So let's do let's say span we'll give.
Give this a class of text primary and inside here we want to put our icon.
So I with the class of F.A. yes.
And then another class this particular icon is F A Dash book dash open.
And we want the word after the icon we want the word edge.
And then outside of the span we want the word ledger because on the edge should be green.
So ledger.
OK.
So that's our logo and then under that we want our navigation which will be a well.
And we want for list items with links.
So we'll say list item we'll use Emmet here so curly braces we can put in the content which will be
in a tag.
We'll just have this go nowhere.
And then we want four of them so we're gonna say times four and hit enter.
Okay.
And if you don't like Emmett if you don't want to do that stuff you can simply type it all out but I
think Emmett makes it much more faster much more efficient and you'll get you'll get used to it.
So home let's do what.
Who and contact and then for the links here.
They're just going to go to the I.D. home the idea of what.
OK.
So these will be sections who and contact.
All right.
Now home as you can see it brings us all the way up to the top.
So I'm going to put the idea of home on the body.
OK.
And this will work even without javascript but it will just kind of click down and it will just go right
down it's not going to have this smooth effect to do that we're using the J.
Query intimate method.
But for now it's just going to kind of click to that area.
All right.
So let's see we have our NAV bar.
So I'm just going to put a comment here and seeing nav bar and if we take a look it's going to look
horrible.
What I want to do is work on each.
Basically each component at a time so we'll do the nav bar then we'll move on to the showcase then this
area this area and so on and we want to style it as we go.
So let's jump into style dot CSX and we'll most likely do the responsiveness after after we get them
the main style down.
So in style dot CSX let's first ad like our our base styles our core our core things that that don't
pertain to specific classes and stuff.
So body lengths asterisk.
We want to add a reset but first thing we want to do is implement our font.
I'm actually using that were a bottle font which is not you know a regular font.
So we're gonna go to Google our fonts dot google and let's search for rubato and right here I'm going
to click the plus sign go down here click on that and I'm actually going to import want to choose this
and I'm going to imported into our CSX file so you can either do that or you can bring it in as a link
tag and your each team Al but I'm just going to go ahead and just do that.
OK.
And once I do that I should be able to use font family rubato.
So we're for our body.
Let's add in that.
Now I'm going to add a little CSX reset here.
We want to make sure our box sizing is border box.
And then I want to just zero out all the margin and padding case or resetting the margin and padding
for everything and then links.
So for lengths I'm just going to remove the underline.
So text decoration underline and I want to add a little bit of margin back to the paragraphs because
remember when we add our reset it takes away margin and padding from everything.
So four paragraphs let's do zero point seven five REM on the top and bottom and zero left and right.
OK.
So take a look.
Looks like this.
Let's see so next thing I want to do is let's take care of the text primary class.
Remember we wrapped this in text primary.
Let's put a space after that icon.
So right here we'll put a space and that pushes that over a bit.
So going to go right here and I'm going to say utility classes do text primary and for text primary
you're gonna do a color and the primary color is going to be nine three C B 5 2 which is gonna be that
green color.
All right.
And if I save that we take a look.
Now that's green.
OK.
Now let's let's deal with the nav bar.
So let's see.
Go right under here.
Let's say nav bar and the nav bar itself.
Let's let's add a background
of 3 3 3 actually save it's going to look like that.
You know what.
Let's kind of what I want to show both at the same time.
So I'm going to just shrink this down a little bit that should be good.
OK.
So we have a background and any anything that's not a link we can add color white.
So if I say this it's not going to change the the links because that's that's a separate color.
And I want to position this sticky.
So I'm actually going to do position for the first value here and let's say sticky and we want to say
top zero.
That's where we want it to stick.
So when we scroll it should stick to the top.
Now I want this to be flex because we want the logo over here we want the menu over here.
Now remember the hotel site we used floats and we're not using floats anymore.
So let's add right here a display of flex and watch what happens as soon as I do that.
Now they're aligned this way not the list items but the whatever is the the child of the nav bar which
if we look is the H1 and the well this dish to children k what what is in those children is irrelevant.
These are the flexi items the NAV and the well.
So those get basically floated horizontally.
Now I want this over here.
Right.
So remember the justified content property.
What that does is it aligns things horizontally.
So I'm going to use space between because I want I want the space to be in between both of the Flex
items.
So let's go ahead and just choose it right here space between and save.
And now that gets pushed over to the side.
So let's see.
Another thing I want to do here is I want to add a z index so a z index is going to it's basically the
position.
I know we went went over this back a while ago but it's the higher the number the closer to the screen
the closer to you it is.
And I want this to always be on top of everything.
When we scroll down so I'm going to put a z index of 1 and that should do it unless we set something
else to z index of 2 or higher than this should go over everything else.
OK.
Hopefully that makes sense.
And then I'm also going to add just a padding value of one room.
So in this case one room is 16 pixels because we haven't touched the eight the root each team.
Font size and that's what REMS are based on.
Next thing we want to do is the well
OK now the U.S. is also going to be flex because we want these to align horizontally so let's say display.
OK.
Remember no more floats display flex save.
There we go.
And then I'm also going to I'm going to do a line items to the center OK so that kind of puts both of
the logo in this at the same level here.
And let's take away the bullet points.
So list I want to do list style.
None.
OK.
And then we also want to deal with the links.
So let's do now Navarre well ally a new color white.
OK so we have our White links.
Wait a minute why is it still underline.
Oh I did text decoration underline there should be none.
All right.
So next thing we want to do is separate them because we don't want them right on top of each other so
let's add a padding here and let's just do zero point seventy five.
Right.
Notice some using REM for for most most things paintings and stuff like that.
And then let's save that see what we get.
Good.
Now I'm also going to add a margin on the one to do a margin on the left and right.
So margin let's do zero and then zero point to five REM on the left and right.
Now when I hover over these I want to have kind of a green box around it.
So let's do the hover state.
So now bar you well ally a colon and hover and let's do a background in the background is going to be
the same green that we have right here.
The Texas primary so we'll copy that paste that in and save that.
Let's check it out OK good.
Now I do want the corners to be a little rounded so let's do a border radius and this is all stuff that
we've done so.
We'll do five pixels and we have a little round on the corners.
All right.
So that's it.
That's our NAV bar.
And as you can see it's it's much cleaner using flex than using floats and stuff like that.
And you know you'll see that you'll realize that as we move along especially with the boxes and stuff
like that.
Also aligning in the showcase.
So that's what we're gonna do next is the whole header showcase area.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.