All right guys next we're going to work on the showcase area.
Now we have our nav bar up here.
So right under the NAV it's got a comment.
And let's just say header showcase really use the HMO five semantic header tag and it's actually given
an idea of showcase.
We don't want to do that.
This doesn't make any sense does it.
I.D. equals showcase.
OK.
So in here we're gonna have a class of showcase dash content.
I want to wrap all the content in that div because this is actually going to be a flex container even
though the elements are gonna be in a column going vertical we still we're still gonna use flex here
and then we're gonna put an H one and I want this H1 to be extra large so I'm actually going to have
a utility class called l dash heading and you're gonna see a lot of similarities through our projects
just different.
Just the neat the ways that I name utility classes and so on and I mean you might come up with different
things but I think everyone has you know their their core class names just the way that they do things
everyone's different and I'm kind of showing you mine and you can adapt it or you can use your own it's
you know whatever you whatever you feel comfortable with.
So we're gonna say the sky is the limit and underneath the h 1 let's put a paragraph from when you use
the class of lead and we're gonna say Lorem 15 who put 15 words in here and under the paragraph we're
going to have an A tag with the class of B.T. and so we can style it.
And it's going to go to idea of what and we're just going to say read more.
OK so we'll just click it and I'll take it.
Take them to the what we do section.
So let's save this.
And this looks like this for now.
So let's head over to our style sheet and let's see let's add comment we'll see a showcase case source.
And we're gonna style the showcase area.
Let's start off with the showcase idea itself.
So for that we're gonna add a background.
This is where we want to add the background image.
So let's do let's do a color of three three three and then we'll do the U.R.L. will do the image over
it which is going to be we want to go dot dot slash because right now we're in the CSX folder we need
to navigate out of it and then into the image folder and then we want showcase dot j peg.
Okay.
And then after that I'm probably gonna have to make this a little bigger after that.
Let's do a no repeat.
And we also want to do center center and we want it to cover the entire area.
Now we've we've gone over this before when we looked at VH units.
It's only going to cover the content.
OK so as far as the content reaches which is to this link it's going to cover that but we wanted to
cover the whole viewport as far as the height goes so let's say we want the height to be 100 VH and
save.
And now it's going to cover the whole viewport.
Now it is going to go a little lower because we have the the menu above it.
So it's basically going to add that spacing there which I don't see a problem you could add a negative
margin if you wanted to kind of pull it up a little bit and kind replace the the menu here but I'm not
going to do that I think that this is fine.
And then let's make the color of everything white and that's inside the showcase all right.
So now we'll do the showcase content.
I'm just gonna make this a little smaller again so make sure this isn't what's size.
Let's say that should be fine.
Well we'll make this a little smaller
All right.
So let's do the showcase content so we have the I.D. showcase and then we have the class showcase content.
So like I said we're going to display flex.
Now as soon as I save that the default is to do a flex row which is horizontal.
Now we don't want that we want a column.
So we're going to add in flex direction column as soon as I do that.
It'll go back to being vertical.
Now we want to align the items center both vertical and horizontal.
So we want it centered this way and this way.
So we're going to use both justified content text a line and a line items.
OK.
So let's first to the text.
So text align center OK and then we're also going to do a line dash actually to justify first or justify
content center.
Now if I do a line dash items center and save notice that it didn't it didn't center it vertically.
The reason for that is there's no height on the Flex container the showcase content.
There is a height on the Showcase which is 100 viewport heights but not on the actual flex container.
So we do have to add a height here.
And for the height I'm going to say I want it to be 100 percent of its container.
So 100 percent of the showcase which is 100 viewport heights once I save that then it will go to the
middle or to the center.
And let's see I'm also going to add some padding here.
Let's do padding zero and then let's do two ram on the left and right and save that.
So that will that should bring in away from the sides a little bit.
Now for the overlay we're going to basically we're going to position this absolute so that we can cover
the entire thing the entire showcase content.
So let's put out a comment here and say overlay and let's to position absolutes and let's say we want
the high already did 100 percent height.
Let's set.
Basically we wanted to start and see let's do top.
Now if I do top zero this is the thing since it's absolute top zero is going to start at the very top
meaning above the the the nav bar.
So let me just show you the top bottom.
Let's just do top left zero and let's add a background dash color and we can use our G.B. a.
So this is red green blue Alpha.
Basically we can do our G.B. so the red green blue values and then Alpha is actually the transparency.
OK.
So I want it to be black with a transparency which goes between 0 1 1 0 0 0 point 1 zero point two all
the way up to 1 which is no transparency at all so black would be all zeros red green blue and then
the opacity or the the alpha transparency whatever you want to call it.
If we said 1 and we save it's just going to there's there's no transparency at all if I do zero point
nine there'll be a little bit transparent as you can see I want zero point four I think that's a good
value.
And now notice that there's it's darker over the image but the text isn't OK.
So we if we just set no positive value on the showcase content the text would also have that opacity
and we don't want that we'd only want the background to have it.
Now as you can see there's some there's some area here that's not covered and that's because of the
nav bar the way that we did this to incorporate the sticky menu.
We have to kind of add a couple that are really hacks but just extra things that we have to do.
So instead of doing top zero I'm going to say top sixty five pixels because that's the the exact number
of pixels of the menu.
So let's save that.
And now you can see that.
It goes all the way.
Actually I think I did a little too much.
Let's do 60 CEO Seo we have this little spacing up here.
Sixty three gnome 60 and yet so that should be good.
Now we have the overlay once we have our responsive our mobile dot CSF CSX we'll have to tweak it a
little bit in the media query because the manual will reach down further because remember that the links
get put under the logo and if you don't want to have the overlay that's fine if you don't want to deal
with the extra properties and hassle you have to.
But I think it makes the text a little more readable.
So next thing I want to do is is this content here which we have a bunch utility classes.
The heading has a class of L dash headings so let's go up to our utilities are and let's add L or class
of L heading.
Let's see the font size for the al heading is going to be for RAM
for RAM.
Save that.
That gets much bigger.
Let's also let's do a margin bottom and for the margin bottom let's do zero point seventy five Ram.
And then I also want a line height of one point one.
So save that.
And if something I do if it doesn't look right to you.
Like if you want less margin or more margin or padding or something feel free to ta ta to mess with
it.
And then this paragraph has a class of lead.
So let's add our class of lead here they're going to set the font size number one room is 16 pixels
I'm going to do one point three ram make it a little bigger and then let's add some margin bottom let's
two to room margin bottom.
Okay.
And then this has a class of B T N so it's do B T N and I wanted to display as an inline block
and I want to add some actually to the color.
So the color is gonna be white and then the background is gonna be that green color which is hexadecimal
and it's gonna be 9 three C B five two.
OK so save that.
We also want some padding for the padding I'm going to do zero point five Ram.
Top and bottom and two Ram left and right and let's do.
Let's see.
Let's do a border.
None.
Because if we happen to add this class to an actual button that's not a link.
Those have borders but we want to remove them but we do want rounded corners so let's do border radius
five pixels.
There we go.
Now I do want to have a hover state so that it changes a little bit on hover.
So let's go over it under it and let's say Beatty and hover and let's set the background to.
Now the background.
It's just gonna be a bit lighter than that green.
I think it's lighter it might be darker but it's seven A B four three six.
And that's all we want is to change the background.
Yeah.
So if I hover over it it gets a little darker.
Now we're also going to add a Beatty and Beatty and dark class and give that a background of dark gray
and a color of white.
In case you want to use that class later.
So I think that that's it for the showcase area.
Actually one more thing I wanted to add on that I forgot was a line height for the body.
So I'm going to do line height one point four.
All right.
That all just you know I think it looks cleaner because it separates the lines a little bit but in the
next video we're going to start on the boxes.
OK.
So we're gonna use flex for that as well and we may move on to the next section we'll see how much time
we have.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.