All right so in the last video we did the header or the showcase area.
So now we're going to move on to the.
What we do section so we're gonna go in the H2 all file directly under the header.
Let's put a comment here or we'll just say section and let's say what we do and we're gonna use in a
show five section tag and we're gonna give this an idea of what.
Now if we look at the final version here we go down to the what we do you can see that there's it's
a light gray background also there's some padding on the top and bottom.
So what I'm going to do is I'm gonna add a class here of BMG dash light and then I'm gonna do a class
of P Y dash one K so remember I think we did this in the hotel website where we had the padding classes
so Pete the Y is the y axis.
Basically we want padding on top and bottom and we'll have p y one two and three and b g lt will be
the the light gray background.
OK.
Now we want to also have a container in here because we want the content to stay in the middle we don't
want it to go all the way over and then we're going to have an H to K and this H two is going to have
a class and I don't want it to be as large as the showcase heading which has a class of L headings so
let's do a m heading for medium so medium heading and then we're gonna have the text primary around
the word What.
K so we're gonna put a span in here with the class of text primary and we're going to say what.
And then after the span put a space and say we do OK.
And then under the H two is where we're going to put our boxes and we're going to just give this a class
of items which is gonna be our Flex container and then inside our Flex container we're gonna have these
three items as flex items so let's just give them a class of item.
So we'll do item times three.
So we have three items and each one is gonna have an icon.
So it's two I class of font.
Awesome.
Also a class of F A Dash university is gonna be this first one here and I want to make it a little bigger
so let's do f a two X that'll increase it increase the size and then I also want a div with the h three.
This one will say investment banking
and then under that let's do a paragraph with law we'll do Lord 10.
OK.
And then I'm just going to copy the I.
The icon and the div and we want to do the same thing in both of these items except we want to change
of course the icon we don't want all the same icons this one is gonna be F.A. book dash reader and then
this last one is going to be FAA dash pencil dash opt in and let's just change the title so this next
one let's do portfolio management and then tax and custodial.
Okay now we'll save that.
Let's take a look at ours.
So it's going to look like this without any styling.
So now let's hop over to style CSX and we don't have the container yet so maybe we should do that first.
So let's see it's basically utility class.
So we'll go right here we'll say container and remember containers that we want to restrict it to a
certain width.
We want to give it a max width which I'm going to do eleven hundred pixels and then let's do margin
auto to make sure that it aligns in the middle.
And then just a little padding.
So I'll do zero top and bottom to ram left and right and let's do overflow hidden.
OK.
So save that and you can see we have some padding here and this is going to stay in the middle no matter
what another class we added was the M heading class actually know what I think I wanted to yeah I will
also want the the headings centred.
So in addition to m heading let's also add a class of text center and we'll go to our style sheet and
let's put text center and I just want that to align the text to the center.
So that takes in text align center.
OK so now that's moved to the center let's do the M heading.
So we should put that right under the L heading I'm just going to copy this and font size for the M
heading s change that is gonna be to REM and the margin bottom will leave that line height I guess we
are we can leave that as well.
So we'll save that.
Good.
So it's a little bigger.
Now we also added that p y one because we need to have some padding here and at the bottom so we might
as will add our padding classes now so I'll go to the bottom of the utility classes actually let's go
right above the button.
It doesn't really matter where you put this stuff but let's do P Y.
Class P Y 1 so padding C padding.
I'm going to do one point five Ram.
Top and bottom.
All right.
And actually know what I'll do is since we only have one property here Let's shorten this up a little
bit and then we'll copy this down and let's do two and three case we need to add more padding so to
Let's do two RAM and then three we'll do three ram.
So if we save that now you can see that we have some padding right here and if you want to make it bigger
you could give it p y two if you want.
OK.
So I think that's good for the utility classes now let's work on the Flex items here and we're also
gonna be styling the icon as well.
But let's take the items so I'm going to go down below the showcase and let's just say
section what we do.
OK.
So we have a class of items that wrap around all three and we want to display as a flex box.
So once we save that it's going to align them in let's take a guy who just make this smaller so we can
see both.
Let's take each item.
See what I want to do here.
Yeah let's take each item in center center all the content so we'll say dot item and let's out of flex
one and let's do text align center and save.
Case looks pretty good.
Let's also add padding to the item actually no one's going to do is add padding to the items itself
so we'll do one room here and then let's also do padding on each item one room and save.
So that kind of spreads it spreads stuff out a little bit.
Now let's see for the icon here.
I wanted to have that green circle around it.
So let's let's target that.
We'll go ahead and do.
Actually no.
Let's let's put the idea of what here.
So what.
And then items and then item we're just better targeting it.
And then here I'm going to say what items item.
And then we want to target the icon.
And we're gonna have a background of our grass green color which is going to be hexadecimal 9 3 C B
5 2 gives it that green and then to make it basically a circle.
Because if I save that it's going to hate how it just goes back up.
But unfortunately we just have to keep scrolling back down.
But you can see we have the green background.
So let's add some padding.
So we'll do one round of padding and to make it circle we want to do a border radius of 50 percent.
OK that'll give it that circle.
So if I saved that then we go.
We just want to add a little margin to the bottom to push the heading down.
So we'll say margin bottom one room.
Here we go.
Now as this gets bigger the reason I'm using.
No we have the widescreen CSX.
Well that's not right.
Okay so something.
What did what did we miss here.
So let's actually go back to the section content because that's where this overlay is.
And I think it's because we have it.
We have position absolute we have top comes down 60 left 0.
We should also add right zero because this is positioned absolute so we'll do right zero and bottom
zero.
So we wanted to start right on the edge.
I'll save that.
And now it brings it back to the edge.
So no matter how big or small this is you can see the overlay still covers it and it should still still
reach the bottom no matter what.
All right.
So sorry about that.
That little mistake there guys.
But anyways yeah when we have a wide screen I actually want the icons to go on the side here but I'm
not going to get into that until we get into the responsiveness we add that we actually start adding
styles to the mobile and the widescreen dot see ISIS file.
So I think that we're good for now and the next section or in the next video where either we're going
to start to work on the WHO WE ARE section which if we look at this it's just basically going to be
an image over here and then some text over here with a list or style it a little bit maybe we can get
the clients in in the next video as well.
All right.
So I'll see you then.