All right.
So now we're going to start on the WHO WE ARE section so right underneath the what we do section.
We're gonna put a comment and let's say section who we are and we're going to use a section tag with
an I.D. of who and you guys can see the the the pattern in how I do things so basically we have a header
at the top or head or NAV combination whatever and then everything under that is usually a section and
that's how I build pretty much all my web sites in you eyes.
So inside this section basically we're gonna have a flex box with two items which is gonna be one the
background image one is gonna be this side here.
And I want it to go all the way to the edge.
So this goes all the way over this goes all the way over so we're not we're actually not going to use
a container in this section.
So the section itself is gonna be the Flex box and then the two items let's do one we'll call it who
Dash I am G.
It's just going to be a background image.
So no no content inside the div and then let's call this one who dash text history of the image in the
way of the text and these are gonna be flexed flex items.
Now the WHO text we're going to also add a couple utility classes I want to add big dark tree stuff
to create and I'm going to do p. 2 I'm going to add some padding classes that have padding all the way
around that's why I don't have P Y P Y is for the up and down access P2 or P anything is going to be
padding all around as you can see that we have here.
So inside here it's put a H two and this H2 is gonna be an M heading so you can see that we we almost
create our own framework when we do this if you have any experience with bootstrap or any kind of each
team LCROSS framework you have built in classes that do certain things and that's pretty much what we're
doing is we're creating our own built in classes so that we can use them over and over instead of styling
you know the the WHO's section H to the what section H H2 and stuff like that we just have these base
utilities that we can use and I think that's the best way to do things.
So who is going to be inside the tech's primary
and if you don't know for instance bootstrap or front end framework like that then you'll see once you
start to learn bootstrap that a lot of these classes I actually take from from bootstrap like text primary
so let's do who and then outside of the span will do we are and then after the H two let's do a paragraph
and I think I did 30 here let's do Lorem 30 and then let's see underneath the paragraph we're gonna
have another h three or h three and we're gonna say our team and then a U L and I'm going to give this
you all a class of list because we need to style it it has some bottom borders take away the the bullet
points stuff like that.
So let's do an ally we have how many looks like what we have five here so times five and we'll just
put some names in here like Mark Smith will say that Mark is the CEO
and let's to Shannon Johnson the CFO
and see John Corbett I don't know where I get these names from a lead accountant
and let's see we have Janet Williams
investment manager and then finally we have Kara Jackson senior accountant and I tried to keep the names
you know with this this image right here actually I'm missing one I the six people here that that's
fine whatever you want to add another one you can.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for the section let's save it let's go back to ours and there we go so it looks
like crap obviously but we're gonna fix that.
So in our style CSX just gonna go ahead and make this a little smaller let's make sure that.
OK so that's still all right.
So let's go under the what section
it's good to keep your your CSX and your age team all commented out just just so you can see you know
what goes where I think it better organizes your your code.
So like I said Who itself the idea of who is going to be the Flex container so let's say I.D. who and
let's say we want to display flex flex and I want just equal sides.
So what I'm going to do is say any div that's inside the WHO div I'm going to say flex 1.
OK.
The divs are the Flex items right.
We have the section which is the Flex box or the Flex container.
And then each of these is the is the is the div or the item and I'm setting it to flex one.
So now it's just split half and half.
Now on this side I want the background image.
So let's do that.
Let's say the idea of who in the class of who dash image I'm going to set the background to a U.R.L.
and the image is gonna we want to go outside of CSX inside of image and we want the people dot J Peg
okay and we're going to add our no repeat.
We're going to center and cover
so now we have our image and then see
over here we shouldn't really have to do anything else we just make this a little bigger.
We shouldn't have to do anything except our utility classes because that'll cover the padding as well
as the background color.
So remember we have a big dark let's go up here where we have the beachy light.
I think we have a big light.
Oh we didn't even add that huh.
No we didn't.
All right.
So let's put that under the text here.
Let's say BFG light which has a background of light gray and color 3 3 3 and then let's also
copy this down and this is gonna be beachy dark
and then beachy dark.
We're just going to kind of reverse this.
So we're going to do 3 3 3 and then for the color let's switch we'll do white for the color colors and
save.
So now this has the light gray this as the dark we need to add some padding here or not add the padding
but add the class of I think we use P to you know use P too.
So let's go right under where we did all these paintings
copy it and I'll do just
do we do a dash.
Yeah P dash 2 so we have one two and three and I'm going to use the same amounts.
So one point five two and three except we want it to be on all sides.
We just want to get rid of the zero because um we just have this one value which will be for all sides
so let's save that.
And now check it out.
We have our padding.
We have our background color.
Well we didn't do is the list.
Now the list is I'm going to make this a utility because we might want to use this less styling somewhere
else so I don't want to I don't want to you know keep it inside the The Who div or the WHO I.D..
So the list I'm going to put under the button here
and let's first of all give it some margin on the top and bottom will do zero point five rim zero.
OK so now it's at least you have some space there.
And then I'm gonna take away the bullet points so list style none.
And for the list items
I'm going to add some padding to the top and bottom zero point five Ram.
And then let's add a border bottom and let's do four for four.
Let's two dotted has a style and one pixel and save.
OK.
So it's pretty good.
All right cool.
So let's see.
I think the clients section is easy enough for us to go ahead and do in this video.
So underneath who we are let's put section clients and we'll do a section with an idea of clients and
I want to add a class of p y one so padding.
It'll be one point five ram on the top and bottom and then we want a container because we want or we
want to move everything to the metal and we want an h to.
I'm going to give this a class of M heading as well as text center and we're gonna say our clients but
the word our will be green.
So we want to do a span here of text primary we'll say our.
And then outside of the span we'll say clients.
Now we're going to use flex again here to align the images so we're going to do a class of items or
let's see.
Let's do um
you know what.
I think you if we look in our style CSX I mean just.
OK.
So we did target what items.
So it's we can use the class items here as well and inside items we're just going to have basically
a div with the image K so the div is going to be the actual flex item.
And then each div will have an image.
And this is gonna be dot slash since we're in the index each time l We want to be in the same folder
and then we want to go into the image folder and then we want to go into logos and I'm gonna do logo
one PMG and we make this a little bigger and then for the all.
I'm just going to say also a client.
OK.
Obviously we don't put anything in here it's just the image but let's copy this down five times and
then we're just going to change the image.
Those will be local five four three and two.
And I'm also just going to add a P1 class here or p y one to add some padding here.
All right.
So let's save that and take a look.
OK.
So obviously it's just going to show it's just each image on a separate line because they're they're
in a div so divs are block level and we haven't we haven't made this a flex box yet.
So we want to do that so that we can align them.
So all right here let's say clients and let's take the client's I.D. and the items class and let's display
that as flex.
Once I do that you'll see that it's going to align them this way.
Now the images are way too big.
They're going off the screen here.
So I'm going to target clients items and then the images themselves.
And for one I'm going to display a block.
OK I want to be able to add a width to them.
I'm gonna say margin auto so that they're right in the center and then I'm going to set the width of
the image to 60 percent of its container and we'll save that.
And there we go.
OK.
So that's that's it for the client section.
So in the next video we're going to start to work on the contact and in the contact we have a little
form here we also have a map case or where we're gonna have to do to implement a map is get an API key
from Google Maps so you will have to log into your Google account and we're gonna use the console to
generate an API key.
OK.
And if and if you don't know what that is.
You know I've never heard of an API key.
Don't worry about it.
We're going to go step by step and we're gonna go through it.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.