OK so now we're gonna work on the contact section which does have a Google map.
We'll probably get to it in this video would if not then we'll we'll get to it in the next one because
I do want to do the form first.
So let's go down to the bottom here.
We'll add another comment for section of contact and let's do a section tag giving an idea of contact
and we're going to have basically I call this contact section is going to be a flex container.
And then the map and the form are gonna be the Flex items.
So the first one will be the form so I'll give it a class of its to contact dash form.
So this will have the form in it and then I'm gonna do a class of map.
Now the Google map that nothing goes inside of here.
Everything is basically done through javascript.
OK so we'll have to look into that after.
But let's add the form for now.
So I'm actually going to also add class of B G dash primary which I don't believe we've done yet but
this is where we have the green background the primary color as the background.
And then I'm gonna do P2 which will give padding all around.
So inside here let's do an H two.
Let's use our M heading class and we'll say contact us.
And then inside the paragraph will say please use the form below to contact us okay.
And then let's do a form.
We don't need an action we're not actually submitting it.
And then here we'll do a class of form dash group which wraps the label in the input.
So label safe for name and then let's do an input with the type of text and the name will be name I.D.
We'll be name and then let's also add a placeholder
and we'll say enter name.
OK.
So if we take a look at that it can see it's very ugly looking for now and then we'll to copy this form
group what's copy this down.
See two three four for these.
The second one is gonna be the email.
So let's change the four attribute to email.
We'll change this to email.
The type will change to email the name and the I.D. email and we'll say enter email for the place holder
K and then we're gonna have phone number.
So this is gonna be phone and let's see the type we'll just keep that as text the name is gonna be phone
I.D. phone and then we'll say enter
a phone number.
And then this last one is gonna be a message.
So for message label message and it's gonna be a text area instead of an input.
So I'm going to get rid of the input in the type and I'm gonna replace that with text area and we need
to add an ending text area tag as well and we'll say enter message for the place holder will change
the name and the I.D. to message as well.
OK.
Now we only we just need to do a submit.
So let's go under the div and let's do an input with the type of submit and the value is just the text
that's gonna read so we'll just say.
I will say send for the value and then I just want a class of B T N and I'm also gonna make this dark
remember we have that B10 and dark class that we created in our C Ss so let's save that and it should
look like this.
OK.
So now let's add the styling for the form we also want to add that big primary right here because we
don't have that as a class.
So let's go up to our utilities go right under big dark and say B G primary in background is gonna be
that this green color.
OK.
And then color is gonna be white.
So that's big primary.
Now down below down at the bottom under the clients section know we'll do a c section clients that's
a section
contact.
Let's see.
So are the contact itself the idea of contact that's gonna be our flex so let's say display flex Kay
now the map.
Let's see I want the contact form and the map by default to have a flex one so that there even when
it's on a wide screen I'm going to change it so that the form is smaller and the map is bigger.
But for now let's take contact in the class of map.
Actually what we can do is just add them both to put a comma and we'll say take contact in the class
of contact form and let's say flex one for both.
So now it's just even now it's style.
The the inputs to label stuff like that.
So the form group so contact and then contact form and then the form group.
I'm just gonna add a margin so that they're separated a bit.
So let's do zero point seven five rems.
OK.
And then we'll do the label because I want the label to display block.
Right now it's in line.
You can see it's you know it's to the left of the input but I want it to be on top.
So let's take.
Contact.
Contact form label and let's display as a block level elements of a save that you'll see that now it's
on top.
All right.
And then for the input in the text area so we'll see.
Contact.
Contact form input as well.
As the text area.
Let's go ahead and set a width of 100 percent.
So it goes all the way across and let's add some padding say zero point five.
And there we go.
So that looks pretty decent now.
Yeah.
Now we'll work on the map.
So what we're gonna have to do is you can have to log into your Google account and then I want you to
just type in search Google console not the search console we want the cloud console because we're working
with a Google map that means that we need an API key because it has to make a request to the Google
servers to get the location and all that stuff.
So let's let's go.
You gonna have to have a project.
OK.
Now I already have one called dev one.
If you don't have a project just do new project call it whatever you want.
Once you have a project if you click over here an API and services it's going to show you.
Let's see right here we want to say enable API is in services and it's going to show you all the different
Google services which there's tons of.
We want maps right here maps javascript API.
OK so you weren't to want to click that mine's already enabled you'll probably see a button that says
enable make sure you click that and then you should see something like this.
Make sure it's enabled.
Mine is as you can see I have a disable option and then you want to go to credentials and you want to
create an API key so let's see.
I mean you can see mine right here.
Where would we go here.
I mean I already have one but you should see something like create new API key I believe.
Credentials API manager.
Here we go.
So create credentials API key and it'll give you something that looks like this and you can restricted
to certain domains and stuff but we're not going to do that just go ahead and save it.
So now you should have an API key.
I'm just going to see you.
I just want to check which one of these I actually used.
Let's see where is it.
Yes.
All right.
So I use this one here so you can actually copy it if you click this it'll copy it to your click clipboard
and for now I'm going to go into my index each team Tim Allen I'm just gonna put this inside of a comment
down here just so I have it all right.
Now next thing we're gonna want to do is go ahead and search for Google Map docs.
And click on the first link here the overview.
And this basically tells us what we need to do.
So we need to add a script tag so a script tag just includes a javascript file and we're including the
javascript maps file.
But we also need to put in our API key.
All right.
And then we need to add a little bit of JavaScript.
Ours is going to be it's going to resemble this but instead of putting it inside of script tags right
in our each team Al we're going to put it in that main J main dot J S file that we created.
And notice that they have a div with the idea of map.
We used a class but it doesn't really matter we can target a div or a class.
And that's where the map goes.
And then you can see up here they set the height to 100 percent because it's like it's like a background
image it needs to have a height or it needs to have some kind of content in it to actually display.
So what we're gonna do is just copy this right here this script.
We're gonna go back into our H team.
I'll go right above the body.
We're gonna pace that in and where it says your API key in all caps.
You're gonna grab your API key and just put it right in there so when it controls C to copy it and then
control V to pace that right in there.
All right.
Now we also need to include our main dot J S file so we're gonna go right above it and put in a script
tag.
So if we do script and then a colon and then S.R. C that will add a source attribute.
OK.
Just like an image when you have an image you point it to a source.
Right.
Well with a javascript file we also use source.
So we're going to point to the J S folder so we can do.
Yeah.
We'll just do J ust slash main Todd J.S. now I mean we're not talking too much about JavaScript in this
course but just remember when you include javascript you use source when you include CSX you use a traffic.
OK.
And when I know that some people when they're starting out they get that confused they'll do a they'll
do link and then source like that or a script tag within a traffic.
Just remember that JavaScript uses the source to attribute.
So that will include the main J S file.
So let's go ahead and save this and then we want to actually go into our main dot J ust file and I'm
I'm gonna actually paste in the javascript and then I'll quickly go over it.
Like I said this is not a javascript course.
I don't really want to get too much into it.
I do have a 21 hour javascript course on you to me if you're interested which I would recommend after
this one.
So I'm going to pace this and you guys can copy this or you can you can get it from the finished project.
And basically what's happening here if we look in the index page Tim Al it's linking to the maps API
and it's it has this callback equals init to map this init map is a function.
OK it's this function here that we're creating.
So it's going to call this in nit map and it is short for initialize and then what we're doing here
is putting in our location which is this is actually called a javascript object and it has a latitude
and longitude.
Now this this latitude and longitude is actually is centred in Boston Massachusetts.
If you want your map to be somewhere else you can get the latitude and longitude from from there.
And there certain sites you can do that with.
So let's just say like get the latitude and longitude from an address and if you go to lat long dot
net you can put in any address here like it or anything.
We could just say like New York
and find and it'll get us just a random place in New York which you can see here so you could put any
any any latitude and longitude that you want into this object.
OK.
But if we're just going to stick with with Boston Massachusetts.
Now this here is creating what's called a variable called map and we're sending it to a new Google map.
And then this document dot query selector is targeting the class of map.
OK.
Now remember in our index each team Al we have this class of map.
So we're targeting that and that's where we want to insert the map and you can change the zoom level.
So we're going to keep it at 14 but you can lower it if you want or higher it.
And then we're saying the center position is going to be in the location K the location was also put
into a variable which is basically a place holder.
And if you don't understand anything I'm saying don't worry about it.
Down here is we're reporting on marker because we want a marker in that special location.
So we're saying create a new marker and the position should be the location which is this variable.
And the map should show this map.
So hopefully that makes at least a little bit of sense of what's going on here.
I don't expect you to know javascript yet.
So let's save this.
And if we go back to our project this is our project.
We have a map.
OK.
So it's as simple as that.
If that was simple maybe that was really hard if you're just getting into this if you're if you're already
familiar with JavaScript and stuff and you've been watching like tutorials and this is probably brutal
for you to watch because it's very it's this at some point this is going to be very simple for you.
But yeah we have our map.
We have our form so good.
Now I think that we can get our footer in here.
That's the last thing on the page.
There's nothing not really anything to it.
So let's head back to index H Tim Al and under our section here let's put in our footer going to use
the footer tag.
And I'm also going to give it an idea of main dash footer.
All right.
And then in here we're just going to put a paragraph with a copy right.
So we'll say copyright.
We'll put our Ampersand copy semicolon remember that we'll say twenty not twenty ninety one be long
gone by then copyright twenty nineteen edge ledger and we'll say all rights reserved for our text and
then actually want to put that in a container so that it stays in the middle so we'll just move this
up into the container and then I want to add some extra classes to this footer.
So let's do b g dash dark and let's do text dash center and then P Y dash one to put the padding on
the top and the bottom and we'll save that and there we go that looks good so we're gonna go ahead and
stop here and in the next video we're gonna add our smooth scrolling which is also javascript.
I'll go over very briefly.
We'll be using something called J query which we'll talk about a little bit but right now I can hit
what brings us down to the what the WHO the menu does cover some of it because the menu is basically
fixed the rest of the site doesn't pay attention to this.
The spacing here so it does start like up here but we can actually kind of work that out with the with
the j query.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.