All right guys.
Now we're going to implement our smooth rolling and we're going to have to use javascript with J query
and I'll explain a little bit about that in a minute but I just want to show you guys something I opened
the site in Safari and with Safari the the position Sticky isn't doesn't work just yet.
So the menu isn't isn't sticking to the top which is fine.
It's not like it breaks or anything it just simply doesn't stick.
But one thing I noticed is the spacing right here and to fix that we actually want to go to want to
go to our style CSX and go to our showcase content and where I have top we actually want to change this
to 65 which I put in the beginning but it wasn't.
It was showing extra space down here because I forgot the bottom zero.
So let's go ahead and save that and notice it still looks fine here.
Everything is good and if I bring safari back in now we don't have that spacing.
OK.
And this you know it still works but it just doesn't stick to the top.
So it's I mean it doesn't hurt to use position stick even though it's not supported in some browsers.
It just makes a better experience if you're in Chrome or Firefox or browsers that do support it.
OK.
So now let's start let's get into the smooth scrolling now to use J.
Query.
Let's go to J.
Query dot com.
Now J.
Query was used all the time years a couple of years ago and it's starting to phase out for things like
dumb Dom selection basically selecting things from the document object model which is basically the
hierarchy of each time all tags and attributes and content in the browser.
Now you can do all this stuff with vanilla javascript which is just regular javascript so there's a
lot of things you don't need a query for that you used to.
However animation is one that is kind of difficult to do and in some situations.
So things like Sly sliders and scrolling effects and stuff J.
Query makes this stuff really easy.
So we're gonna be using it for this.
This one feature now you could download the javascript.
It's just basically a javascript file you could download it.
We're going to use what's called a C D N which we've actually been using with font.
Awesome.
If you look in our index each team I'll file our font awesome CSX is coming from somewhere else right.
It's not it's not located in our local file here.
It's coming from this huge dot font awesome dot com.
So we're going to do the same type of thing with J query.
So I just need to find where we can get the C.D. in here right here using J.
Query with a C.D. And then it stands for content delivery network.
So let's go
Jake right here.
So Jake Query CDM provided by stack path.
No that's not it.
You know I can't find it is because.
OK.
So that's the fire.
I usually just type in J query C.D. And yeah.
So right here code dot J.
Cary dot com and then there's different versions we're gonna choose the latest which is J.
Query three and one thing you don't want to do is choose the slim version the reason for that is with
the smooth scrolling we're actually using the intimate function or the intimate method and that's not
included in the slim version so you can choose the uncompressed which is just the regular JavaScript
file are minute offside which means that all the whitespace is removed all the comments things like
that and it makes your file a little makes it a little faster because it's smaller.
So we'll go ahead and choose the minute fied and then it's gonna give us a script tag that has the J
Cary CDM.
So we can copy this we're actually can just click this that you copy it to your clipboard and then we'll
go back into our index file go down to the bottom and we're gonna pace this in above our main J Yes.
In fact I'm going to put a comment here and say this is our local J.S. file and this is Google Maps
and then above the local we're gonna put our J query C.D. in.
So we're just including the J query JavaScript file from somewhere else.
Now it's important to put it above the main J S because we're using J.
Query inside of this javascript file if we put this below it.
It's not going to know what we're talking about.
OK.
So it's it's important to use this order.
Now we did use Google Maps inside the main J Yes but notice that in the script tag that Google gave
us they use async defer.
So that makes it so that we can actually put it down here and we can still use it in this manger.
Yes.
So let's save this and let's go into our main J.S. and I'm going to just pace this in
and this is our little code snippet for smooth scrolling.
So basically we're targeting the nav bar any link that's inside the nav bar.
Because if we look at our code here.
All right I'm sorry our markup our HD.
We have our whereas it's I.D. nav bar and we're targeting the link k.
So if any link is clicked.
So we're saying on click which is an event then we run a function.
OK.
Now this function we're checking for the hash because when we click this we're basically looking at
these the hash and then whatever the ideas.
And then we're gonna call the animate on the body on the H team Allen body and we want to scroll from
the top to that hash.
OK.
I mean you don't need to understand all this but that's what it's doing it's going to basically do a
smooth scroll and this is the speed at which it's going to do it.
So you can you can make this faster or slower it's in milliseconds so a hundred milliseconds and then
we also want to do it with the class of button.
And the reason I put that there is because if we look at the Showcase we have the read more.
And it goes to the what.
And it has a class of button.
So if we click that I also want that smooth scrolling implemented.
So I'm going to go ahead and save this.
Our main JSA is already being included so it should work.
So we'll go back here and say what.
And it's scroll this down.
And the reason that it's not covering the the title anymore is because I put this in here I basically
said you know we want to scroll down to the I.D. And we want to minus one.
If I don't have this here
so if we do that and we say what you can see it's still covering I go to who is still covering it.
So adding that negative 100 pixels that fixed it.
So now we can actually see the titles.
OK.
So I mean like I said don't worry if that doesn't make sense it's absolutely fine.
I want to add one more snippet of JavaScript so that when we start to scroll this nav bar has a little
bit of opacity a little bit of transparency so we can see through it right now it's completely solid
but I only want to do it when we're not one more so when we scroll down from the top.
So let me just add that in real quick.
So in Maine dot J.S. put that right here and basically this isn't J J query.
This is just regular javascript.
Adding an event to the window.
OK.
So in our in JavaScript you have a window object which is the whole browser and we're listening for
a scroll and we're saying if the scroll y position is greater than 150 basically if we're scroll down
more than one and 150 we're going to select the nav bar and we're going to set the opacity to zero point
nine which will give it a slight transparency.
Else if we're less than 150.
So basically if it's up at the top then the opacity will be 1.
It's not going to be and it's not going to be transparent at all.
So let's save that and notice it's not transparent.
But as soon as I go more than 150 down which is right you'll see it kick in right here.
See how.
Now you can see through it.
If I go up you can't.
That's because we're hitting that 150 position.
And now as we scroll down we can see through it.
So as you can see you can do some really cool things with JavaScript and even J query but we're not
going to get into that.
This course is about H2 on CSX but that's definitely the direction you want to go after this.
But let's let's check it out in Safari while we're at it.
So let me just grab the URL here and yes.
So it's just going to be you know stuck to the top which is fine.
And then another thing I want to do is just get rid of the space and edge ledger.
That should all be one word.
So in the logo let's see we have edge here is this.
Think the space is right here.
Save that.
And yeah.
Now it's all one word.
OK.
So I believe that the just the regular sight is complete.
So all we have to do now is the responsiveness which we have to deal with the menu because if we go
to small you can see it can kind of mess up.
I just want the logo on top.
Have this centered.
And this.
We want these to stack.
We want this.
We want to get rid of the image and just have this clients I want these images to be a little bigger.
We're also going to get rid of the last one so there's only four.
And then we're going to put the map on the bottom of the contact.
Also on wide screens I want the icon here to float or not float but we're going to use flex blocks.
I want it to be aligned to the left as opposed to just being in the middle always.
OK.
Also on tablets if it's like this size I want it to.
I want it to stack.
So that's all stuff that will have to do with the mobile dot CSX and the wide screen dots CSX.
OK.
So hopefully you guys are enjoying this and you're able to follow along and things are making sense.
If a couple things don't.
Don't worry about it.
I mean it happens we're not going to understand every single thing.
The first time around.
So you know it'll it'll come to you in whether it's in this course in the future and in future projects
and in sections or just creating your own projects and so on.
All right.
So that's it.
I'll see you in the next video.