All right so our project is is pretty much done for just regular screen sizes.
But in this video I want to tackle wide screens and just tablets.
And then in the next video we'll deal with smaller mobile devices.
So on wide screens and on tablets I want the the icon here to to basically align to the left.
So I want to turn each item into a flex container so that they go horizontal.
This div and this icon are horizontal even know these are flex items themselves.
They can also be flex containers.
So let's head over actually one thing I want to do before that and then we should have did this in the
beginning.
So we have this style CSM and below the mobile on the wide screen.
We don't want to do that.
We want the original style sheet above those two.
So I'm going to go ahead and just control C copy this and delete it and then move it above the wide
screen and the Mobile case.
We're going to do that and save.
Otherwise the the styles from style C CSX are gonna overwrite what we have in here unless we use important
tags which I don't want to put all over the place.
So let's do that.
Let's open up wide screen dots.
SS And like I said I want to turn each of these items into a flex container so that these are aligned
horizontally.
So to do that let's let's put a comment here we'll say a line icon to left so we'll take the what I
I.D. the items and then the item itself.
OK.
Because each of these have a class of item.
We're going to turn it into a flex block.
So display flex and save.
And notice that.
Now they align this way and don't worry about this we're going to fix that.
Now I want the text now to align to the left not the center.
So let's say text a line to the left and save that.
There we go.
Now for the icon we're gonna do some stuff with that so let's target the icon save position icon.
So we want the what I.D. then items.
Then item and then the eye.
OK.
Because that's that's where that the icon classes and first of all I'm going to add a margin to the
right of one point three REM.
Because as you can see there's no spacing right here so now we're taking this this icon and we're putting
some margin on the right.
So I save the seconds pushed over.
OK.
Another thing I want to do is fix this.
I want to align this in the middle.
So we're going to use the aligned dash self and we want to set that to center and save.
And now that puts that in the center.
And this by default has some margin bottom just from when we had it on the top.
So I'm going to clear that by just saying margin bottom and zero.
OK.
So I think that looks pretty good.
And another thing I want to do on wide screens is I don't want the map in the form to be even I want
the map to take up more space.
So if you remember we have flex one for both of these in fact I'll show you in style CSX.
If we go down here we have flex one for both the map and the contact form so on wide screens I'm going
to take the map and I'm going to add Flex 2 and save.
And now you can see that the map is wider.
And then when I get below eleven hundred it goes back to being even now on small screens and we get
to 768.
I also want I want these to stack on top of each other but I also want them to have the icon on the
left just like with wide screens.
So I'm actually going to copy these two styles here and put them into mobile dots.
SS OK.
Now if I save it it's going to look like that which doesn't look good because we need to stack these
on top of each other meaning we have to remove the flex so right up here.
Let's target what items.
And initially we had it set to flex but now we want to basically clear that flex and say display block
so we'll save that.
Let's add a little bit of a padding one room and there he goes.
Now they're stacked and that looks pretty good.
I mean you could keep it.
He could keep these in the middle like if we remove this and we save.
He could have that but I honestly think that this looks better now.
Every other style that we do in the mobile dot CSX I want to be four or five hundred pixels or less
because tablets tablets should look fine.
In fact if we go ahead and look at our mobile view here with our chrome tools iPhone obviously this
doesn't look good.
The menu doesn't this doesn't this doesn't.
We're gonna have to fix all this stuff.
But for the iPad I think things look pretty good.
It's big enough it's wide enough to keep this flex here and here the menu looks good.
We can even add more links.
And yeah I think that's fine.
So in the next video we're going to target you know iPhone apps iPhone X 6 7 8.
And if it does this with this this side here I'm not sure why that happens.
But notice if I just re save my file that goes away.
So I'm not sure what that is it's some kind of bug.
But yeah I'm gonna just clear this up.
And in the next video we're gonna start to work on basically you know smaller screens that are under
500.
So we're gonna add a media query here for that and we'll put our all of our styles in there.