All right guys.
Now we're gonna start to work on the basically smartphone version of the of the website.
So let's start off with the nav bar because that doesn't look too good.
So in our mobile dot CSX I'm going to add a media query so this is for smart phones.
So let's say at media and we'll say max width of 500 pixels
and let's see.
So we're gonna target the nav bar first right.
So it has an idea of nav bar and I'm going to change I'm going to actually keep the Flex but I'm going
to change the direction because we have it as a row which is horizontal.
Let's change it to column once I save that.
Now you can see that it's going this way instead of horizontal.
And I'm also going to add the A line dash items to the center and save.
And it already starts to look pretty good.
Now the logo I'm going to add some margin bottom I'm also going to make sure I text align it to the
center.
So let's say nav bar let's target the logo and let's do margin bottom and we're gonna do zero point
five REM and let's do text align center and save that did that push it down.
Yeah I did.
Right.
Let's.
Let's move it a little more so we'll do 7 5.
Actually it doesn't seem to be moving does it.
Logo
display none.
So we are targeting it.
OK.
So I guess we'll just move it down a little more.
Let's do one run OK
so let's see for the well
padding actually the Well I think is let's say we had some padding to it.
So I would now bar.
Well
padding.
Zero point five Ram.
Oh that's why I had it.
Because of that padding so let's change this back to zero point five.
Here we go.
OK.
Next thing
if we go down here notice that we now have this space.
That's because the nav bar the height has now grown in what we had before in our style sheet.
If we look at the showcase let's go up to showcase content.
We had top sixty five because that that basically made up for the now bar.
But now the now bar is bigger.
So let's do we're gonna go and say showcase content that's prefixes with I.D. showcase
and instead of sixty five let's say top 110 10 pixels and save.
And now if we go down you can see that there is no more space here.
So that covers it.
And if we make this bigger into the regular size it's fine.
So as soon as we hit 500 pixels it goes into this this menu here.
All right.
So let's see what else what else we have to do here.
So that looks good.
And we'll tell we'll test the devices after this here this this who area.
I want to get rid of the image and actually we're going to remove the Flex from the WHO I.D. because
right now this is a flex box and these two are flex items since we're are removing the this image here.
There's no need for flex.
So let's say who and we'll say display block and if I save that the image is going to go away because
now since the image is in part of a flex box it would need a height to display.
But I don't even want to display it at all so I'm just going to say who.
And then we're going to take the class of who Dash I am G which the image is wrapped in and we're simply
going to say display none OK so we'll save that.
All right so looks pretty good.
Next thing is the clients.
So I mean we could leave it like this but the images are really small.
So what I'd like to do is first of all increase the with so many say clients dot items and grab the
images themselves.
And we have 60 percent by default in style CSF.
Let's change it to 80 and save it.
But I want to remove the last one.
So what we can do is say client's items and grab the div but we want the last child we're going to use
the pseudo selector last child and say display display none.
So if you watch the last logo when I save this it goes away and I think that looks a little better.
They're bigger and there's less of them and we didn't even have to mess with the markup to get rid of
the logo.
Let's see now the contact.
We also want to remove the flax because we want these to stack.
We don't want them to align.
So let's say contact
and actually know we could try.
I did when I initially did this I did display block but let's try flex direction and let's do column
instead and see what that looks like.
OK.
Now the reason we can't see the map anymore is because since it's no longer basically attached to the
form horizontally we need to add a height.
So let's say contact map excuse me and let's say height 200 pixels and save.
Now if we go down we can see the map and I also want to just have a little boy like a black border right
here.
So on the map let's say border top and you can see you can style it however you want on different screens.
I'm gonna do four pixels solid and three three three save.
And now we have square is it pixels light.
P.S. And now we have this border right here which is pretty cool so let's you know.
So once we hit 500 it turns into that
all right good.
Let's see
now the showcase content looks good in a browser but let's actually do the real test and look at it
on the device.
So we're going to open up our chrome tools and check out the device.
OK so this is an iPhone X and I think that looks pretty good.
Yeah.
Everything seems cool so let's check the iPhone 6 7 8 plus.
Good try.
Six seven eight.
Good
and see.
Galaxy Well we could we could move the showcase content up a little bit yeah.
Why don't we do that.
So let's see do we have a showcase content here.
No.
Yeah right here.
So showcase content.
We did top one hundred ten pixels.
Let's do a margin dash top.
But let's do a negative value in this.
What this will do is it will suck the content up.
So notice that right now on the galaxy the read more is kind of it's not in the in the you know the
viewport when you first enter.
I mean you can simply scroll down and it's fine.
But I'd like to just move this up a little bit.
So I'm going to do.
Negative.
It's too negative to REM and save.
And now this is actually in the you know above the fold is what they say.
And then even if we go on like an iPhone X it's still fine it's just up a little more that looks good.
And let's try the iPhone 5.
OK.
So if we wanted to look good on the iPhone 5 which has a very short height what we could do is lessen
the font size of the L heading.
But I'm only going to you know what.
I'm only going to do that if the height is five 68 or less.
Right.
Because this is a height of five sixty eight.
The iPhone 5 the six is six sixty seven.
Everything else is larger than that.
So what I'll do is I'll put an extra media query down here and I'm going to say Max height of five 68
pixels.
And let's take the showcase
actually let me see that again.
No actually we don't need to do the showcase content.
That's fine.
Let's take the L heading
and the original font size I believe is for REM.
So let's say font size and let's set it to three REM and let's take the lead the paragraph has a class
of lead.
We're gonna change that font size to one room which I believe is one point five by default.
And there we go it fits.
So we're targeting 568 height or smaller and then we're at work lessening the font size.
But if we go back to like the iPhone X then the font size is normal.
Actually we have this here though
why is that
that shouldn't be there.
Because we put the top one hundred ten pixels.
Oh is it because of the margin type let me get rid of that.
Yes it is.
It's because.
OK.
So you know what we'll do is we'll only do the margin top negative on heights that are 568 or less.
So showcase content paste that in.
OK.
So that looks good.
Let's go back to the iPhone 5.
Well I guess we still have that problem.
So we have to do is add to the top value.
So we have top one hundred ten.
So let's do top let's try 130 in
showcase.
That could be why I actually wanted to 130 doesn't seem to be enough let's do one 40.
There we go.
OK so the I mean the iPhone 5 isn't really important at least for me.
But I mean it's good to at least have a look decent on older devices.
OK.
So that's going to be it for this project guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed it and you learned quite a bit from it.
If you run into any little bugs or or you know things that aren't displaying quite right on certain
devices maybe you have some some different kind of Android phone and something doesn't look right then
feel free to just tweak it you know go in change some of the values of some of the properties.
I mean this had this Web site obviously isn't like a production Web site that's been fully tested and
and up and running for a while this is something I built for the core so you might run into a couple
things here and they are not just with this project but with any of the projects.
But yeah that's it.
I mean you can use this Web site as kind of a boilerplate or a template for other sites you've just
changed the background image change the colors all that stuff but that's going to be it guys in the
next section.
What I want to do is start to look at Web site deployment because up to this point we've only been building
on our local machine.
So I want to show you how to in probably the simplest way possible to upload a Web site to a shared
hosting account.